# Define quiz data with questions, choices, and correct answers
quiz_data = [
    {
        "question": "1. What is the main purpose of Python's 'virtualenv'?",
        "choices": ["Creating virtual reality environments", "Managing virtual machines", "Isolating Python environments", "Building virtual interfaces"],
        "answer": "Isolating Python environments"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. In Python, what does the 'PEP' in 'PEP 8' stand for?",
        "choices": ["Python Enhancement Proposal", "Programming Efficiency Principle", "Python Execution Process", "Programming Error Prevention"],
        "answer": "Python Enhancement Proposal"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is the purpose of 'pip' in Python?",
        "choices": ["A package manager for Python", "A code editor", "A Python debugger", "A version control system"],
        "answer": "A package manager for Python"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. In Python, what is the purpose of 'Docstrings'?",
        "choices": ["Documenting strings in code", "Defining Docker configurations", "Downloading external scripts", "Creating database connections"],
        "answer": "Documenting strings in code"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Which of the following is a correct way to open and read a file in Python?",
        "choices": ["file.open('example.txt', 'r')", "open_file('example.txt', 'read')", "with open('example.txt') as file:", "read('example.txt')"],
        "answer": "with open('example.txt') as file:"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What is the purpose of the 'self' keyword in Python class methods?",
        "choices": ["Referring to the current instance of the class", "Creating a new instance of the class", "Referring to the parent class", "A placeholder for method arguments"],
        "answer": "Referring to the current instance of the class"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Which of the following is not a valid data type in Python?",
        "choices": ["int", "float", "decimal", "numeric"],
        "answer": "numeric"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is the purpose of 'try', 'except' blocks in Python?",
        "choices": ["Defining a new function", "Handling exceptions and errors", "Creating a loop structure", "Importing external modules"],
        "answer": "Handling exceptions and errors"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. How do you comment out multiple lines in Python?",
        "choices": ["/* This is a comment */", "# This is a comment", "// This is a comment", "''' This is a comment '''"],
        "answer": "''' This is a comment '''"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. In Python, what does the '__init__' method do?",
        "choices": ["Initialize a new Python interpreter", "Initialize a class instance", "Import external modules", "Interrupt the execution of a script"],
        "answer": "Initialize a class instance"
    }
    # Add more questions here
]
